<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Value-based Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/value/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Value-based Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/value/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Value ?</title>
      <link>/value/1.-what-is-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value/1.-what-is-value/</guid>
      <description>As we will see later, a value proposition is at the interface between the firm and its customers, it is characterized by a mix of attributes (e.g. price, availability, reliability, technical specifications, image, ease of use, etc&amp;hellip;). For a transaction to take place the value proposition of a firm must be valued by a customer (willingness to pay) at a level that exceeds the price requested by the firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>/value/2.-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value/2.-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Performance difference is not the rule in all industries and although differences may exist, they are often short lived. Nevertheless some firms, in many different industries, in many different countries and contexts, are doing better than others.
Competitive Advantage Understanding the conditions and factors that control over-performance, has taken center stage in business strategy.
„An enterprise has a competitive advantage if it is able to create more economic value than the marginal (break-even) competitor in its product market, where economic value is the difference between the perceived benefits gained by the purchasers of the firm’s goods or services and the economic cost to the enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Value Capture</title>
      <link>/value/3.-capturing-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value/3.-capturing-value/</guid>
      <description>A Firm transforms inputs into outputs Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs. Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables. Firms acquire the inputs from their suppliers in upstream markets and deliver their products or services to their direct customers in downstream markets.
Capital Equipment: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery, intellectual property) that are not transformed in the process and can be used repeatedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/value/4.-takeway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value/4.-takeway/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>