<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy As a Project on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/TSM/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy As a Project on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/TSM/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/start/</guid>
      <description>Strategy elaboration is likely to mobilize a wide variety of techniques, involve staff from various functional origins and last from a few weeks to several months. It is therefore paramount to plan and organize the work to ensure that resources and means are aligned with expectations and constraints.
Preparing a report, within a week, on the structure of an industry is not comparable with elaborating, along several months, a full diversification strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing a Project </title>
      <link>/TSM/project/establish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/establish/</guid>
      <description>First, consider the &#34;W&#34; It is usually wise to make sure that the Why, for Whom, What, by When and with Whom are sufficiently understood before attempting to defining the How. It is therefore paramount to explicit all the facets of the ”problem” before trying to solve it.
   Problem Statement - (mis-)understanding or (mis-)stating the problem (why do we need to formulate a strategy, why now, about what precisely, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Tools</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/tools/</guid>
      <description>Several tools and technics can be leveraged and this section is not a comprehensive list.
Stakeholder Management Stakeholder Map Stakeholders  are individuals or groups of individuals who depend on an organization to fulfill their own goals and whom, in turn, the organization depends upon.
 Although various versions of stakeholder maps exist, they are all constructed on similar principles. The objective is to plot a scatter graph and to map the power and expectation of the main stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy for your Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/s4s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/s4s/</guid>
      <description>What Strategy for your Strategy? Predictability is not comparable in the oil industry and in the Internet software industry. From this obvious observation, M Reeves, C. Love and Ph Tillmans Reeves et al. (&amp;nbsp; [Reeves12] &amp;nbsp;) derive that companies in very dissimilar competitive environment should be planning and developing their strategies in different ways.
Strategy-Making must match competitive environment nature The oil industry holds few surprises for planners: factors are well identified and outside any single company’s control, barriers to entry are very high, no one is really in a position to change the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>