<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>So what is Strategy ? on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/TSM/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in So what is Strategy ? on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/TSM/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Strategy ?</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</guid>
      <description>What does Strategy mean? “Strategy” in everyday’s conversations In everyday conversations the word strategy far exceeds the domain of strategic management. Considering just a glimpse of the many different meanings, at least three specific contexts can be stressed, in addition to strategic management: strategic thinking, problem solving and important things.
   Strategy for Important it is very common to hear about strategic customers, strategic suppliers, strategic country, strategic campaign, strategic project, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Value ?</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/6.-value-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/6.-value-equation/</guid>
      <description>A Firm transforms inputs into outputs Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs. Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables. Firms acquire the inputs from their suppliers in upstream markets and deliver their products or services to their direct customers in downstream markets.
Capital Equipment: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery, intellectual property) that are not transformed in the process and can be used repeatedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences for practitioners</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/2.-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/2.-consequences/</guid>
      <description>Practitioners have to deal with Ambiguity The word strategy holds a variety of meanings and strategy-making also comes in a vast variety of tastes.
No single definition of &amp;lsquo;what strategy should be&amp;rsquo; is accepted (various people may have different perceptions or expectations). Therefore, dealing with strategy elaboration first and foremost requires building a shared interpretation of the problem to be solved.
When the problem at hand is understood, the strategist must establish as well an adequate problem solving approach and strategy development process and leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Thinking - a primer </title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/3.-strategic-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/3.-strategic-thinking/</guid>
      <description>A notice disclaimer
 Strategic Thinking, a Primer The notion of strategic interaction is one of the core concepts for strategic thinking.
  Let’s assume there is a buffet and we all rush to the refreshments. As a consequence when the last two persons arrive there is only one cup of tea left. These two persons both have two options: either take or don’t take the tea.
This can be represented by a table or matrix, where the rows correspond to one person’s actions and the columns to the other’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/4.-complement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/4.-complement/</guid>
      <description>Ex-post narrative - the Honda Case The now famous Honda Case is a perfect illustration of the difference between deliberate and emergent strategies. It also proves that convincing ex-post stories can be built by analysts who try to report and make intelligible the successful strategic moves and/or missed opportunities of firms.
However, it seems that, in that case (but in how many more ?) the ex-post explanations had totally reconstructed the initial strategic intends and/or deviate from the hard facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/5.-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/5.-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>