<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corporate Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/corporate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Corporate Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/corporate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Strategy</title>
      <link>/corporate/1.-corporate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/1.-corporate/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>/corporate/0.notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/0.notes/</guid>
      <description>Intro  Corporate Strategy refers to the strategy that multi-business corporations use to compete as a collection of multiple businesses. It is qualitatively different from strategy for a single-business or business strategy. (&amp;nbsp; [Puranam16] &amp;nbsp;)  Corporate Strategy being about multi-businesses, it becomes key to define what a business is. The usual accepted definition is that a business is characterized by its business model. So if a firm addresses different segments of customers with radically different value propositions or value architecture, then it is a multiple-business firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/corporate/4.-takeway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/4.-takeway/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options for Growth</title>
      <link>/corporate/2.-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/2.-growth/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Selection</title>
      <link>/corporate/3.-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/3.-selection/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Value</title>
      <link>/corporate/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p3/</guid>
      <description>Business strategy is concerned with how much a specific business can create value. In corporate strategy the central question is ”How can you tell if your company is really more than the sum of its parts?”. i.e. Are the benefits of corporate membership greater than its costs ?
  Corporate strategy should be guided by the vision of how a firm, as a whole, creates value. In any multi-business company, an efficient corporate strategy can contribute to value creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth Pathway</title>
      <link>/corporate/p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p4/</guid>
      <description>Buy Borrow Build M&amp;amp;A are sometimes launched without any sound rationale. This is often viewed as ’the one way’ whereas a more flexible approach (alliance, commercial relationship) would bear more promices. „CEOs suffer from blind spots about alternatives ways of undertaking important changes - Mergers and acquisitions often create more headline than value” (L. Capron).
  Laurence Capron has designed this framework to guide companies and help them select the appropriated growth option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Firm&#39;s Capacities</title>
      <link>/corporate/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p2/</guid>
      <description>Corporate Strategy aims at finding out how a company better Exploit and Enhance its capabilities.
  For the purpose of corporate strategy formulation, resources can be thought as being of two kinds:
 Front-end resources are visible from end-customers and are made tangible in the value proposition (e.g. stores, layout, etc). By extension front-end capabilities also include capabilities that directly deals with customers (e.g. market forecast, market development, marketing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options for Growth</title>
      <link>/corporate/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p1/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Matrices</title>
      <link>/corporate/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p5/</guid>
      <description>Matrices are very often associated with the practice of strategy. A good strategist would have to produce nice looking charts and arrays from which the purpose a firm and key management actions can be derived and illustrated. Reality has become a bit different though. Nowadays, people have learned to become cautious - even sometimes skeptical - when they see nice looking charts.
  It is however important to recognize the most common matrices and understand what they represent (and may be even more important what they don’t represent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Options</title>
      <link>/corporate/p6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/p6/</guid>
      <description>Strategy is about making choice, about allocating resource to the best projects or strategic options.
A firm usually faces several options : for instance developing new products or entering a new business (diversification). Not all the options can be pursued at the same time (remember scarcity of resources). The firm needs to prioritize the various options and down-select the few it wants to implement.
  Even a single strategy elaboration project can produce more than one proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/corporate/toto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/toto/</guid>
      <description>Value Creation through M&amp;amp;A In real life, when a company is acquired, the acquisition price the always higher than the listed price. The difference is called acquisition premium.
In addition to paying the former shareholders, the new owner needs to pay execution costs (to bankers, consultants, etc&amp;hellip;) and post merger integration costs (e.g. alignment of the management information systems, finance reporting, etc&amp;hellip;).
It is also very common that during first months after an acquisition the customer base shrinks: some existing customers decide to switch to other suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>