<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corporate Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/corporate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Corporate Strategy on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/corporate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate composition</title>
      <link>/corporate/1.-corporate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/1.-corporate/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Corporate Strategy aims at finding out if a company should, and if so, how it should compete across several industries.
 Corporate Strategy is about selecting an optimal set of businesses and determining how they should be integrated into the corporate whole - De Wit &amp;amp; Meyer
   Corporate Strategy being about multi-businesses, it becomes key to define what a &amp;lsquo;business&amp;rsquo; is. The usual accepted definition is that a a business is characterised by its business model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth options</title>
      <link>/corporate/2.-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/2.-growth/</guid>
      <description>There are very many reasons (good or sometimes questionable) why a company would seek to grow.
  Growth motivations If we forget fashion effects or &amp;lsquo;prestige&amp;rsquo; motivations it all fall down to three major aspirations:
 Getting access to resources that the mother company needs and that cannot be obtained efficiently from markets
 Financial optimisation that will mostly appeal to Financila investores by also sometimes to CFOs of large coorporations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio selection</title>
      <link>/corporate/3.-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corporate/3.-selection/</guid>
      <description>Strategy is about making choice, about allocating resource to the best projects or strategic options.
A firm usually faces several options : for instance developing new products or entering a new business (diversification). Not all the options can be pursued at the same time (remember scarcity of resources). The firm needs to prioritise the various options and down-select the few it wants to implement.
  Even a single strategy elaboration project can produce more than one proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>