<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management techniques on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management techniques on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Organised</title>
      <link>/management/1.getting-organised/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/1.getting-organised/</guid>
      <description>Strategy elaboration is likely to mobilise a wide variety of techniques, involve staff from various functional origins and last from a few weeks to several months. It is therefore paramount to anticipate, plan and organise the work to ensure that resources and means are well aligned with expectations and constraints.
   Preparing a report, within a week, on the structure of an industry is not comparable with elaborating, along several months, a full diversification case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about Thinking</title>
      <link>/management/2.-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/2.-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Every problem contains within itself
the seeds of its own solution.
 Stanley Arnold   “ The world as we have created it, is a process of our thinking.
it cannot be changed without changing our thinking.
 Albert Einstein   “ Stop thinking and end your problems.
 Lao Tzu  One might be tempted to believe that “thinking” (whether individually or in groups) is a quite natural process, which does not require any special precaution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical Tools</title>
      <link>/management/3.-classical-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/3.-classical-tools/</guid>
      <description>Give me six hours to chop down a tree I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.
 ABRAHAM LINCOLN  There is an endless list of techniques, frameworks and tricks that have their use in strategy elaboration. Almost every new book or article on strategy, put forward a new set of analytical tools, diagnosis canvas or action frameworks.
The objective of this part is to see a glimpse of some of the most common or most used tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/management/4..-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/4..-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>