<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Value Proposition on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/value-proposition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Value Proposition on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/value-proposition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Business Model?</title>
      <link>/value-proposition/1.-what-is-bm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-proposition/1.-what-is-bm/</guid>
      <description>Communication and Self-Reflexion tool The Business Model concept has become common place in many industries and is proving valuable as both a communication and self-reflexion tool. It has also spread to strategic practices as a means of in depth checking of a strategic design.
The stakes are as much in the coherence, consistency of the strategic vision and enterprise architecture as in the ability to mobilize and convince the various stakeholders and materialize the vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Proposition</title>
      <link>/value-proposition/2.-value-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-proposition/2.-value-proposition/</guid>
      <description>A Value proposition is the description of the offer (product or service) made by a company to its customer and why the offer is attractive to customers.
 One of the central questions in Strategy is: which value proposition should be developed? to serve which customer segments?
   Value Propositions compete with a broad set of substitutes. Customers, through their behaviours and consumption logic, determine which companies are actually competing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Ocean Strategy</title>
      <link>/value-proposition/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-proposition/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</guid>
      <description>On the fringe of the two dominant orthodox models (the market-based and resource-based theories) several frameworks have been introduced. They’ve not all made it through. However some frameworks (eg. Blue Ocean Strategy by W. Chan Kim &amp;amp; Renée Mauborgne or Delta model by A. Hax) are becoming popular and are considered valid alternatives or at least good supplements to the dominant models.
  In Hax&amp;rsquo;s words ( [Hax01] ) :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/value-proposition/4..-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-proposition/4..-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>