<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Value Architecture on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/value-architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Value Architecture on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/value-architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Economics</title>
      <link>/value-architecture/1.-business-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-architecture/1.-business-economics/</guid>
      <description>Economists call inputs factors and say that firm combine factors. They also represent the transformation as a so called production function. The function is characteristic of the technology (i.e. production processes) used. For a given production function, the output (and therefore the cost of producing the output) is a function of the various inputs.
  A variation in outputs/inputs will translate into a variation in costs. Moreover the variation in costs in usually not linear (producing more doesn’t necessarily imply overspending in proportion).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance &amp; ROI</title>
      <link>/value-architecture/2.-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-architecture/2.-finance/</guid>
      <description>Return on Investment (ROI) is a broad term that encompasses many different ways of measuring the performance of an investment.
  In general the absolute values of indicators are not meaningful per se. Instead, indicators are used to compare the performance of a firm to other firms from the same industry or across industries. Indicators can also be used to assess performance evolution over time.
A &amp;lsquo;Return&amp;rsquo; on &amp;lsquo;Investment&amp;rsquo; ratio is always some sort of fraction where the numerator measures the performance of a firm and the denominator measures a level of investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Case</title>
      <link>/value-architecture/3.-b-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-architecture/3.-b-case/</guid>
      <description>Business Case One may argue that preparing business cases does not strictly fall within the scope of strategy, and even less of corporate strategy.
  There are however at least three reasons for looking at business cases as part of strategy elaboration:
 Value: strategic moves are about generating value. Although value must here be understood in its widest sense, many stakeholders (starting with shareholders) will measure value in terms of the financial impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/value-architecture/4..-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/value-architecture/4..-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>