<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cover on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/TSM/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cover on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/TSM/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start a SWOT? </title>
      <link>/TSM/tools/swot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/tools/swot/</guid>
      <description>A SWOT chart can be used in a wide variety of situations, which makes it very attractive. It can for instance help evaluating the effectiveness of the existing strategy of an organization (and defining how the strategy should be refined/adapted to changes in the environment). Adequately used, a SWOT can also be very powerful to guide the analysis and very effective to present findings.
The quality of the outputs however, may suffer when the analysis is too superficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/1.-corporate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/1.-corporate/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineating the environment </title>
      <link>/TSM/tools/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/tools/environment/</guid>
      <description>Designing an appropriate model of reality With all Strategic Frameworks, the secret reside in building a model, a simplified view of reality to highlight the key influencing factors.
  The puppet here above has legs with no knee-articulation. If such articulations would be significant for the situation under analysis, the model would be over- simplified. By contrast, adding articulations if not significant at the first order, would bring unnecessarily complexity in the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Organized</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/1.-getting-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/1.-getting-organized/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt (&amp;nbsp; [Sull15] &amp;nbsp;) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/start/</guid>
      <description>Strategy elaboration is likely to mobilize a wide variety of techniques, involve staff from various functional origins and last from a few weeks to several months. It is therefore paramount to plan and organize the work to ensure that resources and means are aligned with expectations and constraints.
Preparing a report, within a week, on the structure of an industry is not comparable with elaborating, along several months, a full diversification strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p1/</guid>
      <description>          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/0.notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/0.notes/</guid>
      <description>Intro  Corporate Strategy refers to the strategy that multi-business corporations use to compete as a collection of multiple businesses. It is qualitatively different from strategy for a single-business or business strategy. (&amp;nbsp; [Puranam16] &amp;nbsp;)  Corporate Strategy being about multi-businesses, it becomes key to define what a business is. The usual accepted definition is that a business is characterized by its business model. So if a firm addresses different segments of customers with radically different value propositions or value architecture, then it is a multiple-business firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options for Growth</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p1/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/4.-takeway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/4.-takeway/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Strategy ?</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</guid>
      <description>What does Strategy mean? “Strategy” in everyday’s conversations In everyday conversations the word strategy far exceeds the domain of strategic management. Considering just a glimpse of the many different meanings, at least three specific contexts can be stressed, in addition to strategic management: strategic thinking, problem solving and important things.
   Strategy for Important it is very common to hear about strategic customers, strategic suppliers, strategic country, strategic campaign, strategic project, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Value ?</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/6.-value-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/6.-value-equation/</guid>
      <description>A Firm transforms inputs into outputs Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs. Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables. Firms acquire the inputs from their suppliers in upstream markets and deliver their products or services to their direct customers in downstream markets.
Capital Equipment: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery, intellectual property) that are not transformed in the process and can be used repeatedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Value ?</title>
      <link>/TSM/value/1.-what-is-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/value/1.-what-is-value/</guid>
      <description>As we will see later, a value proposition is at the interface between the firm and its customers, it is characterized by a mix of attributes (e.g. price, availability, reliability, technical specifications, image, ease of use, etc&amp;hellip;). For a transaction to take place the value proposition of a firm must be valued by a customer (willingness to pay) at a level that exceeds the price requested by the firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Business Model?</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/1.-what-is-bm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/1.-what-is-bm/</guid>
      <description>There are many definitions of the concept of Business Model.
In a nutshell, a BM is a simplified representation of a business that stresses both the intent and inner logic (&amp;nbsp; [Osterwalder10] &amp;nbsp;) .
  A Business Model  is „the set of mechanisms by which a company can create value through the value proposition made to its customers, its value architecture and capture that value to turn it into profits” [Lehmann-Ortega].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the environment </title>
      <link>/TSM/tools/pestel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/tools/pestel/</guid>
      <description>PESTEL The PESTLE analysis is a tool to scan the external macro environment (big picture) in which a business operates or could operate. It aims at pinpointing which of the external factors have the biggest influence on the business (can be either positive stimulus or constraints). It is therefore important that the influence stemming from of the various factors are well understood.
Moreover a PESTLE analysis aims at deciding which of the factors can change the rules of the game in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>/TSM/value/2.-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/value/2.-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Performance difference is not the rule in all industries and although differences may exist, they are often short lived. Nevertheless some firms, in many different industries, in many different countries and contexts, are doing better than others.
Competitive Advantage Understanding the conditions and factors that control over-performance, has taken center stage in business strategy.
„An enterprise has a competitive advantage if it is able to create more economic value than the marginal (break-even) competitor in its product market, where economic value is the difference between the perceived benefits gained by the purchasers of the firm’s goods or services and the economic cost to the enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences for practitioners</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/2.-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/2.-consequences/</guid>
      <description>Practitioners have to deal with Ambiguity The word strategy holds a variety of meanings and strategy-making also comes in a vast variety of tastes.
No single definition of &amp;lsquo;what strategy should be&amp;rsquo; is accepted (various people may have different perceptions or expectations). Therefore, dealing with strategy elaboration first and foremost requires building a shared interpretation of the problem to be solved.
When the problem at hand is understood, the strategist must establish as well an adequate problem solving approach and strategy development process and leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving factors</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p2/</guid>
      <description>          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing a Project </title>
      <link>/TSM/project/establish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/establish/</guid>
      <description>First, consider the &#34;W&#34; It is usually wise to make sure that the Why, for Whom, What, by When and with Whom are sufficiently understood before attempting to defining the How. It is therefore paramount to explicit all the facets of the ”problem” before trying to solve it.
   Problem Statement - (mis-)understanding or (mis-)stating the problem (why do we need to formulate a strategy, why now, about what precisely, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Firm&#39;s Capacities</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p2/</guid>
      <description>Corporate Strategy aims at finding out how a company better Exploit and Enhance its capabilities.
  For the purpose of corporate strategy formulation, resources can be thought as being of two kinds:
 Front-end resources are visible from end-customers and are made tangible in the value proposition (e.g. stores, layout, etc). By extension front-end capabilities also include capabilities that directly deals with customers (e.g. market forecast, market development, marketing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options for Growth</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/2.-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/2.-growth/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Method</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/2.-thinking-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/2.-thinking-method/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt (&amp;nbsp; [Sull15] &amp;nbsp;) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Proposition</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/2.-value-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/2.-value-proposition/</guid>
      <description>A Value proposition is the description of the offer (product or service) made by a company to its customer and why the offer is attractive to customers.
 One of the central questions in Strategy is: which value proposition should be developed? to serve which customer segments?
   Value Propositions compete with a broad set of substitutes. Customers, through their behaviors and consumption logic, determine which companies are actually competing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/TSM/tools/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/tools/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resource &amp;amp; Competence From SWOT to TOWS Once built, a SWOT matrix can also be used to fine tune the analysis of the situation and refine the strategic options. Typically, strategists would look at how to increase competitive advantages by matching the strength and opportunities, while trying to convert weaknesses or threats into strengths and opportunities.
  The four quadrants of the matrix correspond to four distinct responses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Ocean Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</guid>
      <description>On the fringe of the two dominant orthodox models (the market-based and resource-based theories) several frameworks have been introduced. They’ve not all made it through. However some frameworks (eg. Blue Ocean Strategy by W. Chan Kim &amp;amp; Renée Mauborgne or Delta model by A. Hax) are becoming popular and are considered valid alternatives or at least good supplements to the dominant models.
  In Hax&amp;rsquo;s words (&amp;nbsp; [Hax01] &amp;nbsp;) :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Value</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p3/</guid>
      <description>Business strategy is concerned with how much a specific business can create value. In corporate strategy the central question is ”How can you tell if your company is really more than the sum of its parts?”. i.e. Are the benefits of corporate membership greater than its costs ?
  Corporate strategy should be guided by the vision of how a firm, as a whole, creates value. In any multi-business company, an efficient corporate strategy can contribute to value creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economcis</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p3/</guid>
      <description>          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Tools</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/tools/</guid>
      <description>Several tools and technics can be leveraged and this section is not a comprehensive list.
Stakeholder Management Stakeholder Map Stakeholders  are individuals or groups of individuals who depend on an organization to fulfill their own goals and whom, in turn, the organization depends upon.
 Although various versions of stakeholder maps exist, they are all constructed on similar principles. The objective is to plot a scatter graph and to map the power and expectation of the main stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Selection</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/3.-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/3.-selection/</guid>
      <description>The Ansoff&amp;rsquo;s Matrix The famous Ansoff’s matrix was first published in 1957 in the Harvard Business Review. It portrays the four alternative growth strategies, by considering existing products vs. new products, and existing markets vs. new markets.
  Market penetration consists in increasing the business through offering the same product/service to the same market. Market development and Product development are sometimes called related diversification (or adjacent diversification). The idea here is to either offer new products to existing customers or to propose existing products to new markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Value Capture</title>
      <link>/TSM/value/3.-capturing-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/value/3.-capturing-value/</guid>
      <description>A Firm transforms inputs into outputs Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs. Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables. Firms acquire the inputs from their suppliers in upstream markets and deliver their products or services to their direct customers in downstream markets.
Capital Equipment: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery, intellectual property) that are not transformed in the process and can be used repeatedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning the environment</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/3.-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/3.-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt (&amp;nbsp; [Sull15] &amp;nbsp;) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Thinking - a primer </title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/3.-strategic-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/3.-strategic-thinking/</guid>
      <description>A notice disclaimer
 Strategic Thinking, a Primer The notion of strategic interaction is one of the core concepts for strategic thinking.
  Let’s assume there is a buffet and we all rush to the refreshments. As a consequence when the last two persons arrive there is only one cup of tea left. These two persons both have two options: either take or don’t take the tea.
This can be represented by a table or matrix, where the rows correspond to one person’s actions and the columns to the other’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/4.-complement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/4.-complement/</guid>
      <description>Ex-post narrative - the Honda Case The now famous Honda Case is a perfect illustration of the difference between deliberate and emergent strategies. It also proves that convincing ex-post stories can be built by analysts who try to report and make intelligible the successful strategic moves and/or missed opportunities of firms.
However, it seems that, in that case (but in how many more ?) the ex-post explanations had totally reconstructed the initial strategic intends and/or deviate from the hard facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firm Internationalization</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p4/</guid>
      <description>      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/TSM/value/4.-takeway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/value/4.-takeway/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Architecture</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/4.-value-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/4.-value-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs (aka Value Propositions). Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables.
 Note: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery) that can be used repeatedly. Such items are called Capital Equipment and are not transformed in the process.
 Economists call inputs factors and say that firm combine factors. They also represent the transformation as a so called production function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/4.-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/4.-vision/</guid>
      <description>VISION
Strategy is what determines the framework of a firm&amp;rsquo;s business activities and provides guidelines for coordinating activities so that the firm can cope with and influence the changing environment. Strategy articulates the firm&amp;rsquo;s preferred environment and the type of organization it is striving to become - Hiroyuki Itami.
Mission &amp;ldquo;the enduring set of fundamental principles (including the core values, believes, functioning habits) outlining what purpose the organisation wishes to serve, in what domain and under which conditions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/5.-complements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/5.-complements/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt (&amp;nbsp; [Sull15] &amp;nbsp;) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth Pathway</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p4/</guid>
      <description>Buy Borrow Build M&amp;amp;A are sometimes launched without any sound rationale. This is often viewed as ’the one way’ whereas a more flexible approach (alliance, commercial relationship) would bear more promices. „CEOs suffer from blind spots about alternatives ways of undertaking important changes - Mergers and acquisitions often create more headline than value” (L. Capron).
  Laurence Capron has designed this framework to guide companies and help them select the appropriated growth option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p5/</guid>
      <description>                            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Matrices</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p5/</guid>
      <description>Matrices are very often associated with the practice of strategy. A good strategist would have to produce nice looking charts and arrays from which the purpose a firm and key management actions can be derived and illustrated. Reality has become a bit different though. Nowadays, people have learned to become cautious - even sometimes skeptical - when they see nice looking charts.
  It is however important to recognize the most common matrices and understand what they represent (and may be even more important what they don’t represent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy for your Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/project/s4s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/project/s4s/</guid>
      <description>What Strategy for your Strategy? Predictability is not comparable in the oil industry and in the Internet software industry. From this obvious observation, M Reeves, C. Love and Ph Tillmans Reeves et al. (&amp;nbsp; [Reeves12] &amp;nbsp;) derive that companies in very dissimilar competitive environment should be planning and developing their strategies in different ways.
Strategy-Making must match competitive environment nature The oil industry holds few surprises for planners: factors are well identified and outside any single company’s control, barriers to entry are very high, no one is really in a position to change the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/TSM/introduction/5.-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/introduction/5.-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Equation</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/5.-value-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/5.-value-equation/</guid>
      <description>Business Case One may argue that preparing business cases does not strictly fall within the scope of strategy, and even less of corporate strategy. There are however at least three reasons for looking at business cases as part of strategy elaboration:
 Value: strategic moves are about generating value. Although value must here be understood in its widest sense, many stakeholders (starting with shareholders) will measure value in terms of the financial impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Strategies</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p6/</guid>
      <description>                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Options</title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/p6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/p6/</guid>
      <description>Strategy is about making choice, about allocating resource to the best projects or strategic options.
A firm usually faces several options : for instance developing new products or entering a new business (diversification). Not all the options can be pursued at the same time (remember scarcity of resources). The firm needs to prioritize the various options and down-select the few it wants to implement.
  Even a single strategy elaboration project can produce more than one proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/TSM/business-model/6.-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/business-model/6.-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Selection</title>
      <link>/TSM/international/p7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/international/p7/</guid>
      <description>              </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collins&#39; framework</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/p3/</guid>
      <description>James Collins and Jerry Porras in their pivotal research (&amp;nbsp;
[Collins96]
[Collins04]
&amp;nbsp;) offer a framework to clarify the various ingredients of a vision.
  First, they stress that while a company should adapt its strategy to reflect evolutions and changes in its environment, its vision should remain and sustain over time. According to them, ”Vision” provides guidance about what core to preserve and what future to stimulate progress toward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commander Intent</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/p1/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt (&amp;nbsp; [Sull15] &amp;nbsp;) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision, Mission, Strategy</title>
      <link>/TSM/leadership/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/leadership/p2/</guid>
      <description>It became rather standard for companies (at least listed companies) to write Strategy statements with the twofold objective of i) stressing the fundamental goals that the organization seeks (including delineating the scope and domain of their activities, outlining the particular advantages or capabilities they hold) and ii) communicating the underlying and enduring core principles that guide the way the organization should operate.
  Although there is no unanimous agreement on what a vision / mission statement should be, common wisdom sees a firm’s mission as a long-term ambition, preferably enthusiastically phrased, that ensures the identity, consistency and stability of the firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/TSM/corporate/toto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/TSM/corporate/toto/</guid>
      <description>Value Creation through M&amp;amp;A In real life, when a company is acquired, the acquisition price the always higher than the listed price. The difference is called acquisition premium.
In addition to paying the former shareholders, the new owner needs to pay transaction costs (to bankers, consultants, etc&amp;hellip;) and post merger integration costs (e.g. alignment of the management information systems, finance reporting, etc&amp;hellip;).
It is also very common that during first months after an acquisition the customer base shrinks: some existing customers decide to switch to other suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>