<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>So what is Strategy ? on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in So what is Strategy ? on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Strategy ?</title>
      <link>/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/1.-the-nature-of-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Why do we need Strategy? While the overall field of strategic management is rather well delineated, there is very little consensus on What is strategy.
 There are strongly differing opinions on most key issues - and disagreements among practitioners, researchers and theorists as to what is strategy - so deep that even a common definition of the term strategy is illusive ( [DeWit10] )  So even before trying to define WHAT strategy is (at that stage let’s consider that strategy conveys the idea of being successful ), let&amp;rsquo;s first wonder WHY do we need strategy at all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences for Practitioners</title>
      <link>/introduction/2.-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/2.-consequences/</guid>
      <description>Practitioners have to deal with &amp;lsquo;Ambiguity&amp;rsquo; considering that the word strategy holds a variety of meanings and strategy-making also comes in a vast variety of tastes.
  No single definition of &amp;lsquo;what strategy should be&amp;rsquo; is accepted (various people may have different perceptions or expectations). Therefore, dealing with strategy elaboration first and foremost requires building a shared interpretation of the problem to be solved.
When the problem at hand is understood, the strategist must establish as well an adequate problem-solving approach and strategy development process and leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy formulation Process</title>
      <link>/introduction/3.-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/3.-process/</guid>
      <description>To practitioners, strategy is not only an outcome, but also a complete collection of activities, conversations, decision-making exchanges. The strategy formulation process is a typical example of such activities.
  Strategy as Practice is an academic field that complements the mainstream strategy research. It focuses on the practical tasks that contribute to the thinking and making of strategy (e.g. strategy formulation, planning and implementation).
Strategy Formulation Process Four interrelated facets Strategy as a practice encompasses four aspects or facets that are deeply interrelated:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/introduction/4.-complement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/4.-complement/</guid>
      <description>Ex-post narrative - the Honda Case The now-famous Honda Case is a perfect illustration of the difference between deliberate and emergent strategies. It also proves that convincing ex-post stories can be built by analysts who try to report and make intelligible the successful strategic moves and/or missed opportunities of firms.
However, it seems that in that case (but in how many more ?) the ex-post explanations had completely reconstructed the initial strategic intends and/or deviate from the hard facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Thinking - a primer </title>
      <link>/introduction/5.-strategic-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/5.-strategic-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Strategic Interaction The notion of strategic interaction is one of the core concepts for strategic thinking.
  This notion can be rather complex and this section must be seen as a humble introduction to it.
When is an interaction becoming strategic? Let’s assume there is a buffet and we all rush to the refreshments. As a consequence when the last two persons arrive there is only one cup of tea left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/introduction/6.-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/6.-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>