<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business Model on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/business-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business Model on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/business-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Business Model?</title>
      <link>/business-model/1.-what-is-bm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/1.-what-is-bm/</guid>
      <description>There are many definitions of the concept of Business Model.
In a nutshell, a BM is a simplified representation of a business that stresses both the intent and inner logic ( [Osterwalder10] ) .
  A Business Model  is „the set of mechanisms by which a company can create value through the value proposition made to its customers, its value architecture and capture that value to turn it into profits” [Lehmann-Ortega].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Proposition</title>
      <link>/business-model/2.-value-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/2.-value-proposition/</guid>
      <description>A Value proposition is the description of the offer (product or service) made by a company to its customer and why the offer is attractive to customers.
 One of the central questions in Strategy is: which value proposition should be developed? to serve which customer segments?
   Value Propositions compete with a broad set of substitutes. Customers, through their behaviors and consumption logic, determine which companies are actually competing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Ocean Strategy</title>
      <link>/business-model/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/3.-blue-ocean-strategy/</guid>
      <description>On the fringe of the two dominant orthodox models (the market-based and resource-based theories) several frameworks have been introduced. They’ve not all made it through. However some frameworks (eg. Blue Ocean Strategy by W. Chan Kim &amp;amp; Renée Mauborgne or Delta model by A. Hax) are becoming popular and are considered valid alternatives or at least good supplements to the dominant models.
  In Hax&amp;rsquo;s words ( [Hax01] ) :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Architecture</title>
      <link>/business-model/4.-value-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/4.-value-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Any firm, whether it produces products or services, transforms some inputs into outputs (aka Value Propositions). Inputs typically range from raw-materials, labour, intermediate products, consumables.
 Note: the transformation process may also require items (e.g. machinery) that can be used repeatedly. Such items are called Capital Equipment and are not transformed in the process.
 Economists call inputs factors and say that firm combine factors. They also represent the transformation as a so called production function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Equation</title>
      <link>/business-model/5.-value-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/5.-value-equation/</guid>
      <description>Business Case One may argue that preparing business cases does not strictly fall within the scope of strategy, and even less of corporate strategy. There are however at least three reasons for looking at business cases as part of strategy elaboration:
 Value: strategic moves are about generating value. Although value must here be understood in its widest sense, many stakeholders (starting with shareholders) will measure value in terms of the financial impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Away</title>
      <link>/business-model/6.-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/business-model/6.-take-away/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>