<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy &amp; Leadership on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy &amp; Leadership on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision</title>
      <link>/leadership/1.-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/1.-vision/</guid>
      <description>It is now rather standard for companies (at least listed companies) to write Strategy statements with the twofold objective of i) stressing the fundamental goals that the organisation seeks (including delineating the scope and domain of their activities, outlining the particular advantages or capabilities they hold) and ii) communicating the underlying and enduring core principles that guide the way the organisation should operate.
  Although there is no unanimous agreement on what a vision / mission statement should be, common wisdom sees a firm’s mission as a long-term ambition, preferably enthusiastically phrased, that ensures the identity, consistency and stability of the firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start with Why</title>
      <link>/leadership/2.why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/2.why/</guid>
      <description>In its acclaimed book Simon Sinek ( [Sinek11] ) questions Why are some people and organisations more innovative, more influential, and more profitable than others ? Why do some command greater loyalty ?. Sounds familiar ?
Although the book doesn’t deal specifically with strategic management, it covers notions such as leadership and sense of purpose, which ultimately are the key ingredients to successful strategy implementation.
There are only two ways to influence human behaviour According to Sinek Competitive Advantage is an illusion: &amp;lsquo; there’s barely a product or service on the market that customers can’t buy from someone else about the same price, about the same quality, the same features, the same level of features [&amp;hellip;] if you offer something truly novel, someone else will soon come up with something similar and maybe even better &amp;lsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>