<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy &amp; Leadership on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</title>
    <link>/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy &amp; Leadership on Practitioner&#39;s Perspective on Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Organized</title>
      <link>/leadership/1.-getting-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/1.-getting-organized/</guid>
      <description>Strategy elaboration is likely to mobilize a wide variety of techniques, involve staff from various functional origins and last from a few weeks to several months. It is therefore paramount to plan and organize the work to ensure that resources and means are aligned with expectations and constraints.
Preparing a report, within a week, on the structure of an industry is not comparable with elaborating, along several months, a full diversification strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Method</title>
      <link>/leadership/2.-thinking-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/2.-thinking-method/</guid>
      <description>Every problem contains within itself
the seeds of its own solution.
 Stanley Arnold   “ The world as we have created it, is a process of our thinking.
it cannot be changed without changing our thinking.
 Albert Einstein   “ Stop thinking and end your problems.
 Lao Tzu  One might be tempted to believe that “thinking” (whether individually or in groups) is a quite natural process, which does not require any special precaution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning the environment</title>
      <link>/leadership/3.-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/3.-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt ( [Sull15] ) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision</title>
      <link>/leadership/4.-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/4.-vision/</guid>
      <description>VISION
Strategy is what determines the framework of a firm&amp;rsquo;s business activities and provides guidelines for coordinating activities so that the firm can cope with and influence the changing environment. Strategy articulates the firm&amp;rsquo;s preferred environment and the type of organization it is striving to become - Hiroyuki Itami.
Mission &amp;ldquo;the enduring set of fundamental principles (including the core values, believes, functioning habits) outlining what purpose the organisation wishes to serve, in what domain and under which conditions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements</title>
      <link>/leadership/5.-complements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:00:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leadership/5.-complements/</guid>
      <description>Even when it is explicitly formulated, a strategy does include detailed actions for all stakeholders. On the contrary, it should focus on top level considerations and ensure alignment, while leaving a lot of freeway to the people in charge of executing.
  Organization alignment D. Sull &amp;amp; K.M. Eisenhardt ( [Sull15] ) have rightly pointed out that if an organization’s strategy lives on the shelf then this organization has a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>